<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drafts on Tracking Exposed</title>
    <link>te.fmdj.fr/drafts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drafts on Tracking Exposed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 15:32:40 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="te.fmdj.fr/drafts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysis &amp; Publications</title>
      <link>te.fmdj.fr/drafts/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 15:32:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>te.fmdj.fr/drafts/work/</guid>
      <description>2021 — 2020 — 2019 — 2018 — 2017 — 2016  2021 event Published in: May    E-privacy 2021, Italian conference on privacy and digital rights   Due esempi di bias algoritmici: la polarizzazione su Youtube e l&amp;#39;eteronomartività su Pornhub. Gli algoritmi sono una soluzione tecnologica al sovraccarico di informazioni: sono tanto potenti quanto necessari per gestire l&amp;#39;overflow di dati che ci raggiunge. Purtroppo, possono anche nascondere l&amp;#39;uso di valutazioni e giudizi basati su bias che hanno un impatto sulla diffusione delle idee e della cultura.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With passion and commitment, since 2016</title>
      <link>te.fmdj.fr/drafts/work2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 15:32:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>te.fmdj.fr/drafts/work2/</guid>
      <description>Publications (display)   Events (display)   Press (display)   Monthly Reports    
Accademic Articles  YTTREX: Crowdsourced Analysis of YouTube’s Recommender System During COVID-19 Pandemic. Pdf, Project updates, Call to action. by Leonardo Sanna, Salvatore Romano, Giulia Corona, Claudio Agosti (Communications in Computer and Information Science, 05/2021). Political advertising exposed: tracking Facebook ads in the 2021 Dutch elections by Davide Beraldo, Stefania Milan, Jeroen de Vos, Claudio Agosti, Bruno Nadalic Sotic, Rens Vliegenthart, Sanne Kruikemeier, Lukas P Otto, Susan A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>for TRex collaborators 😵 THE MOST DIFFICULT TASK EVER 😵</title>
      <link>te.fmdj.fr/drafts/internal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 15:01:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>te.fmdj.fr/drafts/internal/</guid>
      <description>Dear friend! If you did something for tracking.exposed: cool! Sadly, your effort is not over yet, until your action gets adequately reported in our production list. The file is of ‘analysis-and-publication’! our list of project’s success and yours should be there too. We should save each advocacy effort. Articles published that talk about us, and of course our productions.
You&amp;rsquo;ve to edit (or propose a pull request) to this file on github, which become like a list of events in the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are we up to?</title>
      <link>te.fmdj.fr/drafts/connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 18:11:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>te.fmdj.fr/drafts/connect/</guid>
      <description>We operate in small, mono focus, projects*. &amp;ldquo;Facebook&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Pornhub&amp;rdquo; are two mono-focus projects for us. &amp;ldquo;European Election algorithm analysis&amp;rdquo; is another one.
All the volunteers contribute freely expecting acknowledgment for their effort and offering quality time. Generally, we team up with people and organization who understand and share the manifesto. Being proactive in developing an idea is extra appreciated, as per Autumn 2019, we run understaffed and underfunded. We don&amp;rsquo;t have solutions for these issues yet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
